Your son is arrived from London.
你儿子从伦敦回来了
- Father ... - John ...
-爸... -约翰...
You will see in my will the estate of Norland was left to me in a way -
我在遗嘱有交代... 我当初继承诺兰庄园的条件是...
- that prevents me from dividing it between my two families.
我们两家不能分祖产
Norland, in its entirety, is therefore yours by law.
因此...诺兰现在依法归你所有
And l am happy for you and Fanny.
我为你和芬妮感到高兴
But your stepmother, my wife and daughters are left only 500 a year.
但你继母...我的太太和你姐妹们 每年祗得5百英镑
Barely enough to live on. Nothing for the girls' dowries.
仅能糊口 你的姐妹们的嫁妆都没有着落
- You must help them. - Of course.
-你一定要帮助她们 -这当然
You must promise to do this.
你一定要向我保证
l promise, Father. l promise.
我保证，父亲 我保证
Help them? What do you mean?
帮她们？什么意思？
l mean to give them 3,000. The interest will be an extra income.
我想要给她们3千英镑 所赚得的利息钱也不无小补
- The gift will fulfil my promise. - Without question. More than amply.
-这份礼物就算我履行承诺 -当然，这就够多了
One had rather. on such occasions. do too much than too little.
这种事情，宁可要大方一点
Of course, he did not stipulate a particular sum.
当然，爸又没有指定要给多少
What do you say to 1,500, then?
那你觉得1千5百英镑如何？
What brother would be so kind to his real sisters. let alone half-blood?
别人对亲妹妹都没这么好 更何况是同父异母
- They can hardly expect more. - What can you afford?
-她们不能奢望太多 -问题是你能给多少？
100 a year to their mother is better than losing 1,500 at once.
每年给继母100英镑 总比一次拿1千5百英镑好
Should she live longer than 15 years we'd be completely taken in.
她若再活15年以上 那我们岂不是亏大了
People live forever when an annuity is to be paid them.
人一有年金可拿就会比较长寿
20 now and then will amply discharge my promise, you're right.
偶尔给个20英镑也就行了 你说得对
l'm convinced that your father had no idea of giving them money.
我相信你父亲 也没指望你拿钱给她们
- They will have 500 a year. - What more could they want for?
-反正她们一年会得到5百英镑 -她们还奢求什么？
No housekeeping, carriage, horses, few servants, keeping no company ...
她们根本没开销，既没有马 也没几个仆人，又不交朋友...
How comfortable!
这样的日子算是很富裕了
They will be much more able to give you something.
她们说不定还有余力给你钱
Marianne. can you play something else?
玛丽安，你可否弹别首曲子？
Mamma has been weeping since breakfast.
妈从一早哭到现在
l meant something less mournful.
我是指比较不悲伤的曲子
A visitor in my own home! lt is not to be borne. Elinor.
竟然叫我们反客为主！ 我咽不下这口气，爱琳娜
- Mamma, we have nowhere to go. - John and Fanny will be here soon.
-妈，我们无处可去 -约翰和芬妮马上就到了
Do you expect me to be here to welcome them? Vultures!
别想叫我满脸笑容的欢迎他们 贪得无厌！
l will start making inquiries for a new house at once.
我马上开始找房子
Until then, we must try to bear their coming.
在此之前，我们必须要忍耐一下
Margaret, are you there? Come down, John and Fanny will be here soon.
玛格丽特，你在上面吗？快下来 约翰和芬妮马上就到了
Why are they to live at Norland? They have a house in London.
他们为什么非得来诺兰住？ 他们在伦敦有房子
Houses go from father to son, not father to daughter. lt is the law.
因为房子是传子而非传女 这是法律的规定
- Come, we'll play with your atlas. - lt's not mine. it's their atlas.
-走，我们去玩你的地图集 -不是我的，是他们的了
Do sit down.
请坐
We are looking for a new home, and can only retain Thomas and Betsy.
我们在另找房子 搬家后，祗能雇用汤玛士和贝丝
We're sorry to have to leave you all.
很遗憾我们得分手了
But we are certain you will find the new Mrs. Dashwood a fair mistress.
不过我们相信新女主人， 戴太太会好好善待各位
My only real concern is how long it will take them to move out.
我祗关心她们何时才会搬走
- How is Mrs. Ferrars? - She is always in good health.
-费洛斯太太好吗？ -家母身体一向很好
My brother is with her this season. Quite the most popular bachelor.
舍弟在伦敦陪她 他可是个万人迷
He has his own barouche.
他有一辆敞蓬马车
- You have two brothers? - Yes. Edward is the elder.
-你有两个弟弟吧？ -对，大的叫爱德华
He's travelling up from Plymouth and will break his journey here.
他要从普利茅斯来这住几天
- lf that is agreeable to you. - Dear John ...
-当然如果你们同意的话... -亲爱的约翰
This is your home now.
现在这个家是你们的了
- Fanny wants the key to the silver. - What does Fanny want with it?
-芬妮要餐具柜子的钥匙 -她要干嘛？
One can presume she wants to count it. What are you doing?
想必是要清点，你在干嘛？
Gifts for the servants. Where is Margaret? She's taken to hiding.
给雇人的礼物，你有看到 玛格丽特吗？她到处躲
- At least she can escape Fanny. - You've not said a word to her.
-至少她可以躲开芬妮 -你也没跟她说半句话
l have. l've said yes and no.
我有呀！ 我有说“是”和“不是”
Good morning, Fanny.
早安，芬妮
Good morning, Miss Marianne.
早安，玛丽安
How did you find the silver? Was it all genuine?
餐具怎么样？都是纯银的吧？
- When may we expect your brother? - Edward is due tomorrow.
-令弟什么时候来？ -爱德华明天会到
He will not stay long. Will Margaret give up her room for him?
他不会待太久 玛格丽特的房间能否让给他？
The view is incomparable, and l want him to see Norland at its best.
那房间的景致最美 我想让他瞧瞧诺兰之美
Mrs. Dashwood. Miss Dashwood. Miss Marianne.
这位是戴太太 戴小姐，玛丽娜小姐
My brother, Edward Ferrars.
舍弟爱德华费洛斯
Do sit down.
请坐
Where is Miss Margaret? l'm beginning to doubt of her existence.
玛格丽特呢？ 我不禁开始怀疑她的存在了
Forgive us, Mr. Ferrars. My youngest is shy of strangers at present.
费先生，请您原谅 么女最近很怕生人
l am shy of strangers myself, and l have nothing like her excuse.
我自己也怕生人 却不像她有个好理由
How do you like your view, Mr. Ferrars?
还喜欢窗户外的景致吗？ 费先生
Very much. Your stables are handsome and beautifully kept.
很喜欢，你们的马厩很漂亮 打理得很好
Stables? Your windows overlook the lake.
马厩？你窗外应该是一池湖水
An error led me to a family room, but l've rectified the situation.
我原本被带到主人房间 我发现错误之后
l am happily installed in the guest quarters.
便住在客房，那里很舒适
Tea!
喝茶吧！
They're all spoilt. Miss Margaret is always up trees and under furniture.
她们都被宠坏了 玛格丽特很爱爬树到处躲
l've barely had a civil word from Marianne.
玛丽安也没对我说上半句好话
They've just lost their father. Their lives will never be the same.
她们的父亲刚过世 生活情况完全改观
That is no excuse.
这不是藉口
Library.
书房
- These are mostly foreign. - lndeed. Magnificent.
-这些大部份是外文书 -真是太棒了
l've never liked the smell of books.
我讨厌书的味道
The dust, perhaps. l hear you have great plans for the walnut grove.
也许是灰尘的缘故吧 听说你胡桃园兴工
l shall have it knocked down to make place for a Grecian temple.
我要把把它铲平 盖一座希腊式神殿
That does sound interesting. Would you show me the site?
听起来不错 你要不要带我参观一下？
Too expensive, and we do not need four bedrooms. We can share.
太贵了，况且我们不需要 4间卧房，可以合睡
This one. then.
那这个好了
We have only 500 a year.
我们一年祗有500英镑
l'll send out more inquiries today.
我今天再写信打听
Pardon my intrusion, but l think l have found what you're looking for.
恕我打扰了，我想我已经... 找到你们所想要找的
Won't you come out? We haven't seen you all day.
你出来好不好 我们有一整天没见到你了
We'll have to enlarge it. Mattocks will help you adjust to our hours.
要加盖 雇人会告诉你时间的
Forgive me, do you by any chance have a reliable atlas?
对不起 你们有没有一本好的地图？
- l believe so. - l must check the Nile's position.
-应该有的 -我想查尼罗河的位置
My sister tells me it is in South America.
我姐姐说是在南非
No! No, she's quite wrong.
不对！ 不，她搞错了
l believe it is in Belgium.
应该是在...比利时
Surely not. You must be thinking of the Volga.
不会吧？你讲的是窝瓦河
- The Volga, which starts in ... - ln Vladivostok. and ends in ...
-窝瓦河的源头是在... -海参崴，流到...
- Wimbledon. - Yes. where coffee beans come from.
-温布登 -没错，那里产咖啡豆
The source of the Nile is in Abyssinia.
尼罗河的源头是在阿布西尼亚
ls it? lnteresting.
是吗？真有意思
- How do you do? Edward Ferrars. - Margaret Dashwood.
-幸会，爱德华费洛斯 -玛格丽特戴虚伍
lt adjoins this property, and would be a desirable addition.
他家就在旁边 能买下来就太好了
- l'll ride there and speak to ... - Gibson.
-我会去找他谈谈...他姓什么？ -吉伯森
- He'll be pleased enough to sell. - He'll want more than it is worth.
-他应该很乐意出售才对 -他一定会漫天喊价
Have l hurt you?
痛不痛？
Thank you. Forgive me.
谢谢 对不起
That was my father's favourite.
这是父亲生前最喜爱的曲子
Thank you for helping Margaret. She's changed since you came.
谢谢你关照玛格丽特 你来了之后，她好了很多
l enjoy her company.
我喜欢有她作陪
- Has she shown you the tree house? - Not yet.
-她有带你参观树屋吗？ 还没有
Would you do me the honour, Miss Dashwood?
你能否...带我去看，戴小姐？
- lt is very fine out. - With pleasure.
-今天天气很好 -我很乐意
- Margaret always wanted to travel. - l know. She's off to China soon.
-玛格丽特很喜欢旅行 -我知道，她最近很想去中国旅行
l'm to go as her servant, on the understanding l'll be badly treated.
要我当她的仆人 当然她不会亏待我
- What will your duties be? - Sword fighting and swabbing.
-你的工作会是什么？ -比剑和打扫
Which will take precedence?
哪个优先？
All l have ever wanted is the quiet of a private life.
我祗求生活平静安逸
But my mother is determined to see me distinguished.
但我母亲要我出人头地
Orator. Politician. Even a barrister would do. if l drove a barouche.
演讲家，政治家，甚至律师也行 祗要我有豪华马车
What do you wish for?
你的希望是什么呢？
l prefer the church, but that is not smart enough for my mother.
我一直想当神职人员 但我妈认为不够光彩
She prefers the army, but that is too smart for me.
她喜欢我从军， 但这对我而言太光彩了
- Would you stay in London? - l hate London.
-你会住在伦敦吗？ -我恨伦敦
Country living is my ideal. A small parish where l might do some good.
我喜欢住在乡下 在小教区行善
Keep chickens ... Give very short sermons.
养养鸡...讲道而不废话
You feel idle and useless. lmagine how that is compounded -
你说你觉得游手好闲 一个人没有工作
- when one has no choice of any occupation whatsoever.
没有任何选择时那才难过呢！
Our circumstances are therefore precisely the same.
我们真是同病相怜
Except that you will inherit your fortune.
但你将会继承巨额财产
We cannot even earn ours.
我们连想赚点钱都不能
Perhaps Margaret is right. Piracy is our only option.
也许玛格丽特说得对 干脆去当海盗算了
What is swabbing exactly?
拖地要怎么拖？
''No voice divine the storm allayed. No light propitious shone.''
“天不从人愿，风暴未歇 吉光未现”
''When snatched from all effectual aid, we perished, each alone.''
“奥援竭绝，我们逐一死去”
''But I, beneath a rougher sea, and whelmed in deeper gulfs than he ...''
“而我，更逢惊涛骇浪 即将葬身深海”
No. Edward.
不对，你听我念
''No voice divine the storm allayed. No light propitious shone.''
“天不从人愿，风暴未歇 吉光未现”
''When snatched from all effectual aid, we perished, each alone.''
“奥援竭绝，我们逐一死去”
Can you not feel his despair? Try again.
你能体会到他的绝望吗？ 再来一次
''No voice divine the storm allayed. No light propitious shone.''
“天不从人愿，风暴未歇 吉光未现”
''When snatched from all effectual aid, we perished, each alone.''
“奥援竭绝，我们逐一死去”
Mamma ...
妈...
Look. This has just arrived.
你看，这是刚刚才收到的
''l should be pleased to offer you a home at Barton Cottage, as soon ...''
我很乐意 提供巴顿小屋给你们居住...
- lt's from Sir John Middleton. - Even Elinor must approve the rent.
-是约翰爵士寄来的 -爱琳娜一定不嫌贵的
- Has she not yet seen this? - No. l will fetch her.
-她还没看过这信吗？ -我去告诉她
Wait, let us delay.
等等，晚点再告诉她
l believe that Edward and Elinor have formed an attachment.
我相信 爱德华和爱琳娜互相喜欢
lt would be cruel to take her away so soon. Devonshire is so far.
我不忍叫她这么快走 迪凡郡太远了
- Do you disapprove her choice? - By no means.
-你觉得他不适合她？ -没有啊！
- Edward is very amiable. - Amiable? But ..?
-爱德华很和善 -和善？可是呢
There is something wanting. He is too sedate. His reading ...
可是总缺少了什么 他太严肃了，他读诗的样子...
Elinor has not your feelings.
爱琳娜不像你
Can he love her? Can the soul be satisfied with polite affections?
他真的爱她吗？ 如此相敬如宾就能满足吗？
To love is to be on fire. Like Juliet. Guinevere. Heloise.
爱一定要热情如火 就像是茱莉丽、亚瑟皇后一样
- They made rather pathetic ends. - Pathetic? To die for love?
-结果都是悲剧收场 -悲惨？为爱而死？
- What could be more glorious? - Your romantic sensibilities ...
-有什么比这更荣耀？ -你的感情未免太丰富了
''ls love a fancy or a feeling? No, it is immortal as immaculate truth.''
“爱情是梦幻还是感觉？ 不，它跟真理一样永恒”
'''Tis not a blossom shed when youth drops from life's stem.''
“不似花朵自然凋落”
''lt grows without water, nor ray of promise cheats the pensive gloom.''
“爱能生于无水荒漠 不怕缺乏阳光滋润”
A pity Edward has no passion for reading.
可惜爱德华的朗诵不行
You asked him to read. then you made him nervous.
是你叫他念的，害他紧张
Your behaviour is cordial. You like him in spite of his reading.
你待他还很客气，虽然他 念得不好，但你还是喜欢他
l think him everything that is amiable and worthy.
我觉得他...很和善、可敬
Praise. indeed.
真会夸人
He shall have my devotion when you tell me he is to be my brother.
但如果你要嫁给他 我会好好待他
- What shall l do without you? - Without me?
-我没有你怎么办？ -没有我？
I'm sure you will be very happy, but promise you won't live far away.
我相信你一定会幸福的 但答应我，千万别住得太远
- There is no question of ... - Do you love him?
-不可能的... -你爱他吗？
l do not deny that l think very highly of him. That l ...
我不否认我觉得他很好，我...
... greatly esteem him. l like him.
非常尊敬他，我喜欢他...
Esteem? Like? Use these words again and l shall leave the room!
尊敬？你再这么说，我就走了
Believe my feelings to be stronger. Further than that. do not believe.
我的感觉是更强烈 但更进一步倒也没有
ls love a fancy or a feeling?
爱情是梦幻还是感觉？
- Or a Ferrars? - Go to bed.
-莫非是姓费才叫爱 -上床睡觉吧
''l do not deny that I think very highly of him.''
“我不否认...我觉得他很好”
''That l ... greatly esteem him.''
“我...很尊敬他”
''That l like him.''
“我喜欢他”
We are so happy that you invited Edward to Norland.
我们很高兴你邀请爱德华来
We're all very fond of him.
我们都很喜欢他
We have great hopes for him. Mother expects much of him.
我们对他期望很高 家母对他的期望最高
And in marriage. She's determined both he and Robert will marry well.
婚姻也一样，她要他 跟罗伯娶个门当户对的媳妇
But l hope she desires them to marry for love.
希望她要他们为爱结婚
The heart doesn't always lead us in the most suitable direction.
但光靠感情 未必会找到适合对象
Edward is a compassionate person. Penniless women prey on that type.
爱德华心肠很好 容易受穷女人骗
Having entered into an understanding he would never go back on his word.
一旦说定，绝不会食言
But it would lead to his ruin.
不过这也会毁了他
l'm worried. Mother will withdraw all financial support from him -
我很替他担心 家母已表明她不会给他分文
- should he plant affection in less exalted ground than he deserves.
如果他所爱的人不是门当户对
l understand you perfectly.
我了解了
Devonshire?
搬到迪凡郡？
My cousin, Sir John Middleton, has offered us a small house.
我表亲约翰爵士 提供一处小房子给我们住
He must be a man of property.
他一定很有钱
He's a widower from Barton Park. It is Barton Cottage he has offered.
他太太去世了，跟岳母住在 巴顿公园，他把小屋租给我们
A cottage? Charming. A cottage is always very snug.
小屋？真可爱 住小屋最舒服了
You will not leave before the summer?
你们夏天才去吧？
We can no longer trespass upon your sister's goodwill.
我们不能再打扰了
- You will come and stay with us. - l should like that.
-你会来住几天吧？ -我很想去
Edward has long been expected by our mother.
家母已在伦敦等候很久了
Come as soon as you can, Edward. Remember, you're always welcome.
爱德华，有空来走走 记得，我们随时欢迎
- Can't you take him with you? - We can't afford him.
-不能带它走吗？ -我们养不起
Perhaps he could make himself useful in the kitchen ... Forgive me.
叫他在厨房帮忙，对不起
Miss Dashwood ...
戴小姐...
Elinor ... l must speak to you.
爱琳娜...我有话要跟你说
There is something of great importance that l need to ...
有件很重要的事，我必须...
... tell you ... about my education.
...跟你说... 是在念书时候的事
- Your education? - Yes.
-念书时候的事？ -是的
lt was conducted. oddly enough, in Plymouth.
我是在...普利茅斯念的书
- Do you know it? - Plymouth? No.
-你很熟吗？ -普利茅斯？不熟
l was four years there.
我在那里念了四年的书
ln a school run by Mr. Pratt.
学校校长是布来特先生
- Pratt? - Precisely. Pratt.
-布来特？ -没错，布来特
While l was there ...
我在校期间...
That is to say, he had a ... has a ...
我是说，他当时... 他有个...
You're needed in London this instant.
你得立刻启程去伦敦
- l'm leaving this afternoon. - Mamma wishes you to leave at once.
-我今天下午就走 -妈要你马上动身
Excuse me.
失陪了
Edward promised he would bring the atlas to Barton.
爱德华答应我会带地图集来
l'll wager he will do so in less than a fortnight.
我打赌他会在二星期内赶到
Dear Edward ...
可爱的爱德华...
Hello there!
大家好！
Sir John ...
约翰爵士...
Dear ladies! Upon my word! Here you are!
太太小姐们...可被我盼到了
- Sir John, your kindness ... - None of that! Hush, please!
-约翰爵士，你太客气了 -别跟我客套，别吵
Here is my dear mamma-in-law, Mrs. Jennings.
这位是我岳母詹宁斯太太
You must be Mrs. Dashwood. Was yourjourney tolerable? Poor souls!
你一定是戴太太 一路上累了吧，真可怜
Why did you not come up to the park first?
怎么不先来我家坐坐
- We saw you pass. - l made John call the carriage.
-他看到你们经过 -我马上请约翰备车就来了
- She would not wait. - We have so little company.
-她可是急性子 -这一带朋友少嘛
l feel as though l know you already. Delightful creatures!
但我们真是一见如故 小姐们还真漂亮
- You'll dine at Barton Park daily. - Dear Sir John. we cannot ...
-你们每天一定要来家里吃便饭 -亲爱的约翰，这怎么行呢
No refusals! l'm quite deaf to them. But l insist!
我不接受拒绝 我不管那么多，就这样了
Let us settle in. But thank you very much.
等我们先安顿好再说，谢谢你
Send your man up for the carriage as soon as you're ready. Goodbye.
忙完后 叫人来通知我们一声，再见
Don't thank us.
别谢了
Your feet are cold.
你的脚好冰
What have you been doing? You can grow potatoes in this dirt.
你怎么弄的？ 这么脏，都可以种菜了
lt's cold. l'm cold.
好冷喔
Where can Brandon be? l hope he's not lamed his horse.
布莱登跑哪去了？ 不会是他的马跛了吧？
Col. Brandon is the most eligible bachelor in the county.
布上校 是本郡最有价值的单身汉
He is bound to go for one of you. He's a better age for Miss Dashwood.
你们其中一位可以嫁给他 以他的年纪比较适合戴小姐
But l dare say she's left her heart behind in Sussex.
就怕她早已名花有主
l see you, Miss Marianne! l think l've unearthed a secret.
我瞧见了玛丽安 秘密被我发现了
You are worse than my best pointer.
你比我最棒的猎犬还差呢
ls he a butcher. baker. candlestick maker? l'll winkle it out of you.
他从事哪一行？ 士农工商？我非打听到不可
- She's good at winkling. - We've none of us any secrets here.
-她是包打听 -这里可没有秘密
Or if we do. we do not keep them long.
就算有也不会维持太久
- He's curate of the parish. - Or perhaps a handsome lieutenant.
-我敢说他是神职人员 -或者是英俊的军官
- Give us a clue. ls he in uniform? - He has no profession.
-来点暗示吧，他穿不穿制服？ -他没职业
He's a gentleman?
他是位绅士？
- You know there is no such person. - There is. His name begins with F.
-你明知没有这个人 -就有，他姓的开头是F
F? A promising letter.
F？这就有眉目了
Foster? Forrest? Fotheringay? Featherty?
佛斯特？ 福瑞特？福林葛？佛斯提
- Fortescue? - Fondant?
-佛泰斯秋？ -佛顿
Might l play your pianoforte?
我能否弹你们的钢琴
Yes. of course.
当然可以
- We don't stand on ceremony here. - Please forgive ...
-大家不要这么拘束 -约翰爵士，请原谅...
l cannot remember when we last had a song in the house.
上回听歌是哪一年来着？
Brandon! Come and meet our beautiful new neighbours.
布莱登！ 过来见见我们美丽的邻居
What a pity you're late. You have not heard our songbird.
真可惜你来迟了 你没听到玛丽安美妙的歌声
A great pity.
确实很可惜
This is my good friend Col. Brandon. We served in the East lndies.
这位是我的好友，布莱登上校 东印度的老战友
- Not a better fellow in the world. - You've been to the East lndies?
-天下没有比他更好的人 -你去过东印度群岛？
- What's it like? - Hot.
-那里是什么样子？ -热得很
The air is full of spices.
空气中全是香味
Now. Miss Dashwood. it's your turn to entertain us.
戴小姐，现在轮到你表演了
And l believe l know what key you will sing in.
我知道你要唱什么调...
F-major ...
F大调
You have no right to parade your ignorant assumptions ...
乱猜的事你还到处乱讲
- You told me. - l told you nothing.
-是你说的呀！ -我什么也没说
- They'll meet him when he comes. - You don't speak of such things.
-反正他要来 -这种事不能随便说
- Everyone else was. - Mrs. Jennings is not ''everyone''.
-大家都在说 -祗有詹太太
l like her. She talks about things. We never talk about things.
我喜欢她，她爱聊天 我们从不聊天
lf you can say nothing appropriate, limit your remarks to the weather.
想不到合适的话题 就谈天气好了
Surely they have enough reeds for a Moses basket.
编再大的篮子也够了
You know what they're saying?
你知道外面的传言吧？
Word is, you've developed a taste for certain company. And why not?
人家说你看上一个人， 有何不可？
A man like you in his prime ... She'd be a fortunate young lady.
你正值壮年...这是她的福气
Marianne Dashwood would no more think of me than of you.
玛丽安看不上我这种人
- Don't think of yourself so meanly. - And all the better for her.
-别小看自己 -这样才省她的事
Besotted ... An excellent match.
真是陶醉...他们是天作之合
- He's rich and she's handsome. - How long have you known him?
-他富有，她标致 -你认识他多久了？
As long as l've been here, and l came 15 years back.
打从我来这里就认识他了 15年了
His estate is but four miles hence. He and John are very thick.
他家离这里祗有四英哩 他和约翰又是至交
He has no wife and children. He had a tragic history.
他没有妻儿 他有段辛酸往事
He loved a ward to the family. They were not permitted to marry.
他爱上了一个人 但因为家人的反对而没结果
- On what grounds? - Eliza was poor.
-为什么？ -为了钱，伊丽莎很穷
She was flung out of the house, and he was packed off to the army.
她被逐出家门，而他被迫从军
l think he'd have done himself harm if not for John.
要不是约翰，我想他会想不开
- What became of the lady? - She was passed from man to man.
-那位小姐后来呢？ -她换了好几个男人
She disappeared from good society.
上流社会就再也没她的踪迹
When Brandon returned from lndia he searched and searched. -
布莱登从印度回来后 就一直在找她
- only to find her dying in a poorhouse.
在收容所找到时 她已经去逝了
l thought my daughter Charlotte might have cheered him up.
我以为女儿夏洛特 可以令他开心
Look at him now! So attentive!
但你看他！多体贴呀！
- l should try a little experiment. - Please. let the colonel alone.
-让我去试探一下 -别去捉弄他吧
All suitors need a little help.
所有的追求者 都需要有人推一把
- We haven't heard you play of late. - You have a superior musician here.
-我们好久没听到你弹琴了 -有高手在此，何必班门弄斧
Brandon shares your passion for music. He plays the pianoforte well.
布兰登跟你一样喜爱音乐 他可是钢琴高手
You know as many melancholy tunes as Miss Marianne.
你和玛丽安一样 知道很多哀伤的曲子
You must play us a duet. Let us see you both side by side.
来个二重奏好了 你们合奏一曲
l do not know any duets. Forgive me, Colonel.
我不会弹二重奏 抱歉，上校
Will we never have peace? The rent is low. but it comes on hard terms.
难道我们没有宁静的一天吗？ 房租虽然便宜，但却要受气
Mrs. Jennings has nothing to do but marry off everyone else's daughters.
詹太太有钱有闲 她喜欢替人作媒
There's a parcel arrived.
有人送包裹来
Look!
你们看！
When is a man safe from such wit. if infirmity does not protect him?
他又老又虚弱 怎会还有人开这种玩笑？
lf he is infirm. then l am at death's door.
他是虚弱的话 那我不早就是行尸走肉
- He complained of rheumatism. - ''A slight ache'' was his phrase.
他自己说有风湿 他祗说“一点痛”
Edward said he would bring it himself.
爱德华说他要亲自拿来的
''lt gives me great pleasure to restore this atlas to its owner.''
“谨将地图集物归原主”
''Business prevents my delivering it, which will hurt me more than you.''
“公事缠身，无法亲自奉还 遗憾之至，恐甚于各位”
''Memories of your kindness must sustain me. and l remain -
“感谢各位的盛情 吾将永志难忘”
- your devoted servant, E.C. Ferrars.''
“祝安，E.C.费洛斯.”
- Why hasn't he come? - He says he's busy, dear.
-他为什么不来？ -亲爱的，他说了他很忙
- He said he'd come. Why hasn't he? - l'm taking you for a walk.
-他说会来的，为什么不来？ -我带你去散步
- lt is going to rain. - lt is not going to rain.
-快要下雨了 -不会的
l fear Mrs. Jennings is a bad influence.
我觉得詹太太效应要出现了
- You must miss him. Elinor. - We are not engaged, Mamma.
-你一定很想念他，爱琳娜 -妈，我们又没有订婚
- But he loves you, dearest. - l am by no means assured of that.
-可是他爱你，亲爱的 -我不清楚他怎么想
And had he such a preference, there would certainly be obstacles -
就算他有意思，也不代表... 他能娶一位...
- to his marrying a woman of no rank who cannot afford to buy sugar.
...没地位、 连买糖都嫌贵的女人
- But your heart must tell you ... - lt is better to use one's head.
-但你心知肚明... -以现在这情况最好用大脑去想
- lt can't be good for me. - lt is. Stop complaining.
-这怎会对我好？ -会的，别抱怨了
- lt's giving me a cough. - lt is not giving you a cough.
-会害我咳嗽的 -不会的
lt's lovely. Come on, catch up!
这样很棒的，快跟上！
- Over there is a field of rabbits. - l don't want to see rabbits.
-那里有好多兔子 -我不想看兔子
- ls anything superior to this? - l told you it would rain.
-还有什么比这更快乐？ -我说会下雨吧！
- Blue sky! Let us chase it! - l'm not supposed to run.
-蓝色的天空！快追！ -我不可以跑的
Are you hurt?
有没有受伤？
- l cannot walk. Run and fetch help. - l will run as fast as l can.
-我不能走了，快去找人帮忙 -我尽量跑快点
Margaret!
玛格丽特！
Don't be afraid. He's quite safe.
别害怕，它不会伤害你的
- Are you hurt? - Only my ankle.
-你有没有受伤？ -祗伤到脚踝
May l have your permission to ascertain if there are any breaks?
我能否看看你是否有骨折？
lt is not broken.
骨头没事
Can you put your arm about my neck?
手扶着我脖子好吗？
Allow me to escort you home.
让我送你回家吧
At last!
总算回来了！
She fell down and he's carrying her!
她摔倒了，他抱她回来！
Marianne, are you hurt?
玛丽安，你没有受伤？
lt's a twisted ankle.
她扭伤了脚踝
lt's not serious. l felt the bone. and it's sound.
伤得不严重 我看过骨头了，没事
- l cannot begin to thank you. - Do not think of it.
-不知该怎么谢你才好 -没什么
- Will you not be seated? - l'd leave a water mark.
-请坐 -我会把椅子给弄湿了
- But permit me to call tomorrow. - We shall look forward to it.
-我明天能来探望吗？ -欢迎之至
l'll show you out.
我送你出去
Margaret, get the gentleman's hat.
玛格丽特，这位先生的帽子
- His name! - To whom are we so much obliged?
-问他叫什么名字！ 请问先生尊姓大名？
John Willoughby of Allenham at your service.
约翰卫乐比，我住艾伦汉
John Willoughby of Allenham ...
艾伦汉的约翰卫乐比
What an impressive gentleman!
真是一位绅士！
He lifted me as if l weighed no more than a dried leaf.
他抱我完全不费吹灰之力
- Tell me if l hurt you. - She feels no pain, Mamma.
-会痛就告诉我 -妈，她不会痛的
Margaret, ask Betsy to make up a cold compress.
玛格丽特，请贝丝准备冷敷袋
Please don't say anything important.
等我回来再继续说
- He expressed himself well. - With decorum and honour.
-他风度真好 -很有礼貌，人品不错
- And spirit and wit and feeling. - And economy. Ten words at most.
-有活力、又机智富同情心 -话不多但句句重点
- Change, or you'll catch a cold. - What care l for colds?
-快换衣服，免得着凉 -着凉算什么？
- You'll care when your nose swells. - You're right. Help me.
-等你鼻塞，就会在乎了 -你说的对，快帮我
He's worth catching. Marianne must not have all the men to herself.
卫乐比的条件很好 但玛丽安不能要谁就有谁
- But what do you know of him? - There's not a bolder rider.
-你对他了解多少？ -他的马术不错
But what are his tastes. his passions, his pursuits?
他有何嗜好，作何消遣？
- He has a smart little pointer ... - Where is Allenham?
-他的猎狗很灵敏... -艾伦汉在哪？
Nice little estate three miles east. He is to inherit it from a relative.
三哩外的小庄园 他的亲戚将留给他
Lady Allen is the name.
那位亲戚就是艾夫人
lt's Col. Brandon. l should go out and keep watch.
是布上校，我去外面看着
You're looking out for Willoughby. You'll not think of Brandon now.
你们都在等卫乐比 没人会去想布莱登了
Come in.
请进
Good morning, Brandon.
早安，布莱登
- How is the invalid? - Thank you so much, Colonel.
-病人怎样？ -谢谢你，上校
Why set your cap at Willoughby when you've already made such a conquest?
你有这么好的对象 何必再想着卫乐比？
l'll not set my cap at anyone.
我没有想着任何人
- Lady Allen's nephew? - He visits. for he's to inherit.
-艾夫人的外甥是吗？ -他来看所将继承的土地
He has a pretty estate of his own. Combe Magna in Somerset.
他自己有个漂亮的庄园 在索梅塞的科柏美那
l'd not give him up to a younger sister for tumbling down hills.
换了我也会舍不得放弃 这个好机会
The man himself. Come. Brandon. We know when we are not wanted.
他来了，走吧，布莱登 我们最好要识时务
Thank you so much for calling.
谢谢你们来
Marianne. the colonel and Sir John are leaving.
玛丽安 布上校和约翰爵士要走了
Goodbye. Thank you for the flowers.
再见，谢谢你送的花
- How do you do, Colonel? - How do you do, more like.
-你好吗，上校？ -问候你自己吧！
- Mr. Willoughby, what a pleasure! - The pleasure is all mine.
-卫乐比先生，真高兴再见到你 -完全是我的荣幸
- Miss Marianne has not caught cold? - You've found out my name.
-玛丽安小姐没有感冒吧？ -你知道我的名字了
The area is crawling with my spies. You cannot venture out to nature ...
这里到处有我的眼线 你无法接近大自然...
- So nature must be brought to you. - How beautiful.
-大自然就得来接近你 -好美
- These are not from the hothouse. - Mine is not the first offering.
-这不是温室里的花朵 -原来有人送过花了
- They come from an obliging field. - l always prefer wild flowers.
-这是从田野里摘的 -我一向喜欢野花
- Would you ..? - Our gratitude is beyond words.
-帮我放在花瓶里 -我们感激万分
l've grieved for this lonely house. Then l heard it was taken.
我常经过这孤零零的房舍 听说有人住进来
l felt an interest which nothing can account for but my present delight.
听说之后就有预感会遇见你们 果然如此
Pray sit, Mr. Willoughby.
请坐，卫先生
Who is reading Shakespeare's sonnets?
谁在读莎翁的十四行诗？
- Marianne is reading them out. - And which are your favourites?
-玛丽安念给我们听 -你们最喜欢哪一首？
Mine is 1 16.
我最喜欢第116首
''Let me not to the marriage of true minds admit impediments.''
“心灵契合，突破阻碍”
''Love is not love which alters when it alteration finds. -
说变心就变心...哪能算是爱...
- or bends with the remover to remove ...''
或者任凭抹灭...
- How does it continue? - ''No. it is an ever fixed mark ...''
-接下来呢？ -“不，爱是永不褪色的印记”
- ''That looks on tempests...'' - ls it ''tempests''?
-纵有狂风暴雨... -是“狂风暴雨”吗？
lt's strange you are reading these. l carry them with me always.
没想到你也读这个 我随时带在身边
Until tomorrow then ...
明天见
My pocket sonnets are yours. A talisman against further injury.
袖珍诗集就送给你好了 给你当护身符
Goodbye. Thank you.
再见，谢谢你
Good work. Marianne. You covered Shakespeare, Scott, poetry.
不错嘛，玛丽安 你们谈了莎翁和其他诗词
When you know his views on romance, you'll have nothing left to talk of.
等你知道他对爱情的看法后 你们就没有话题了
l suppose l erred against decorum. l should have talked of the weather.
我想我的确不矜持 我应该祗谈天气
Mr. WilIoughby can be in no doubt of your enthusiasm for him.
卫先生明t你对他的兴趣
Should l hide my regard?
我干嘛要隐藏？
- No. but we know so little of him. - Time does not determine intimacy.
-毕竟我们对他所知不多 -亲密程度不在时间长短
Seven years is too little for some, seven days is enough for others.
有些人相处七年还是不熟 但对有些人而言七天已足够
- Or seven hours. in this case. - l feel l know him already.
-对你们而言祗需七个小时 -我觉得我对他已经很了解了
Had l more shallow feelings, l could perhaps conceal them as you do.
我要是隐藏我的感觉， 才会跟你一样
- l'm sorry ... - Don't trouble yourself, Marianne.
-对不起... -用不着解释
l do not understand her.
我真不了解她
Marianne ...
玛丽安...
- Haven't you finished yet? - No. Patience.
-画完了没？ -还没，要有耐心
You're not going to deny us beef as well as sugar?
糖不买了，牛肉也不买了吗？
- There is nothing under ten pence. - Do you want us to starve?
-肉都好贵 -你要我们饿肚子吗？
No. Just not to eat beef.
不是，祗是不吃牛肉
lf my behaviour was improper, l should be sensible of it.
如果我的行为真的失当 我自己清楚
lt has caused impertinent remarks. Do you not doubt your discretion?
外面已经传得很难听了 你不觉得你应该反省吗？
lf Mrs. Jennings' remarks prove impropriety, we are all offending.
若要理会詹太太的话 那我们不就都难过死了
Good morning, Colonel.
早，上校
Miss Dashwood. Miss Marianne. l come to issue an invitation.
戴小姐，玛丽安 我是来邀请你们的
A picnic on my estate at Delaford.
我要在庄园举办野餐
lf you would care to join us on Thursday next.
请你们参加 是在下星期四
Mrs. Jenning's daughter and husband are travelling up especially.
詹太太的女儿和女婿也会来
We should be delighted, Colonel.
我们很乐意参加，上校
l will, of course, be including Mr. Willoughby in the party.
我当然也会邀请卫先生
l should be delighted to join you.
我很乐意参加
Good morning, Miss Dashwood. Good morning, Colonel.
早安，戴小姐 早，上校
The colonel has invited us to Delaford.
上校邀请我们去他家作客
- l hear you have a fine pianoforte. - A Broadwood Grand.
-听说你有部好钢琴 -布洛伍钢琴
- Then l shall play for you all. - We shall look forward to it.
-那我可以弹给你们听 -我们等不及了
- Your sister seems very happy. - She does not hide her emotions.
-令妹看起来很开心 -她这个人从不隐藏情绪
Her romantic prejudices tend to set propriety at naught.
她对爱情的定义 往往使她忘了礼仪
- She is wholly unspoilt. - Rather too unspoilt.
-她真是天真浪漫 -是太天真了
The sooner she is acquainted with the ways of the world, the better.
她愈早认清这个世界愈好
l knew a lady with the same sweetness of temper -
我认识一个人很像令妹 个性一样冲动、可爱
- who was forced into a better acquaintance with the world.
后来她被迫认清了这个世界
The result was only ruination and despair.
结果是痛苦绝望
Do not desire it. Miss Dashwood.
能免则免，戴小姐
Col. Brandon's lawn is perfect for kite launching.
布上校的草坪最适合放风筝了
Mind the pretty ribbons.
要小心彩带
lmagine my surprise when Charlotte and her master appeared with Lucy.
我事前不知道 夏洛特一家人跟表妹露茜会来
The last person l expected to see.
真是太意外了
She came to join in the fun. There is no such luxury at home.
她是来玩的 家里没钱办活动
l'd not seen you for so long.
好久没见到你
You sly thing! lt was the Dashwoods she wanted to see.
你骗人！你是要见戴小姐
l've heard nothing but ''Dashwood'' for l don't know how long.
她整天戴小姐长，戴小姐短的
What do you think of them? My mother wrote of little eIse in her letters.
露茜，你见着了，觉得如何？ 母亲在信里都写你们的事
- Are they not as she described? - Nothing like.
-妈形容得一点也没错吧？ 错得离谱
You are quite rude today.
你今天真没礼貌
He's to be an MP. and he is forced to make everybody like him.
他要当议员 要讨人喜欢，所以很累
- l said nothing so irrational. - Mr. Palmer's so droll.
-我哪会说这种离谱的话？ -看他脾气变来变去的
Here he comes! Now you shall see, Charlotte.
他来了！ 夏洛特，你快看看
Hello, Mr. Willoughby!
卫先生，你好
You must meet my daughter Charlotte, and Mr. Palmer.
来见见我女儿夏洛特和巴先生
- And our cousin, Miss Lucy Steele. - Welcome to our party.
-和我的小表妹，史露茜 -欢迎
May l sit beside you?
我能坐你旁边吗？
l've longed to meet you. I've heard nothing but praise for you.
我早就想认识你 大家对你推崇之至
Sir John and Mrs. Jennings are too excessive in their compliments.
约翰爵士他们太会夸奖人了
The praise came from another source. One not inclined to exaggeration.
夸你的是另有他人 而他不会随便赞美人的
What can this be?
怎么回事？
ls Col. Brandon here?
布莱登上校在吗？
- My horse! - What's the matter?
-快牵我的马来！ -怎么回事？
- l must away to London. - lmpossible!
-我得马上赶到伦敦 -这怎么行？
We can't picnic without our host. Come up to town tomorrow.
野餐没有主人怎么可以 明天再去吧
- Or wait until we return. - l can't afford to lose one minute.
-或等野餐结束，才几个小时 -一分钟也耽误不得
- Forgive me. - l hope it's nothing serious.
-请原谅 -希望问题不严重
Upon my soul, this is all very unusual.
这可真反常
- Frailty, thy name is Brandon. - Some cannot bear pleasure.
-脆弱，你的名字叫布莱登 -有些人见不得人家开心
You are a wicked pair. Col. Brandon will be missed.
你们好坏 布上校不在好可惜
Why? Everyone speaks well of him, but no one remembers to talk to him.
为什么？每个人都说他好 却都不怎么理他
Nonsense. He is highly respected at Barton Park.
胡说 约翰爵士他们都很敬重他
- Which is enough censure in itself. - Really, Willoughby.
-这等于是在骂他 -卫乐比，你也真是的
Come, come, Mr. lmpudence. l know your wicked ways.
过来，傲慢先生 我知道你爱乱搞
Reveal your beau. No secrets between friends. l'll winkle it out of you.
快说你的情人是谁，朋友之间 是没有秘密的，我帮你
l'll have you married to the colonel by tea, or l'll swallow my bonnet.
我要你嫁给上校 否则我马上吞帽
- As if you could marry him. - Why should you dislike him?
-好像他配得上你似的 -你为什么不喜欢他？
Because he threatened me with rain when l wanted it fine.
因为我要晴天，他却爱雨天
He found fault with my high flyer and will not buy my brown mare.
他爱挑我马车的缺点 又不肯买我的马
If it will be of satisfaction to you, -
但为了满足你
- l believe his character to be. in all other respects, irreproachable.
我愿意说 他在其他各方面是完美无瑕
ln return for this acknowledgement, don't deny me the privilege -
我既然忍痛承认 就请允许我...
- of disliking him as much as l adore ...
讨厌他，就如同我喜爱...
... this cottage.
这间小屋
- l have plans for improvements. - That. l will never consent to.
-我计划要整修房子 -这点我绝不赞同
Not a stone must be added to its walls.
一瓦一砖也不许增加
Were l rich enough, l'd rebuild Combe Magna to this exact image.
我若有钱 就会把家拆掉照这间重新建造
- With a fire that smokes? - Especially the fire that smokes.
-你喜欢冒烟的壁炉？ -尤其是会冒烟的壁炉
Then l'd be as happy at Combe as l've been at Barton.
如此我在家就和在这一样开心
But this place has one claim on my affections none other can share.
但我对这房子有特别的感情
Promise never to change it.
答应我不要改变它
l'm honoured you risk your honour by seeing me to the gate unaccompanied.
你不怕被说闲话送我一程 让我受宠若惊
- That is what Elinor would say. - And she would be right.
-爱琳娜也会这么说 -她说得对
Miss Marianne, will you grant me an interview tomorrow ... alone?
玛丽安 明天能否和我单独见面？
- Willoughby, we are always alone. - But there is ...
-卫乐比，我们一直都是如此 -可是...
There is something very particular l should like to ask you.
我有特别的事要问你
Of course. l shall ask Mamma if I may stay behind from church.
当然 我会请妈让我不必上教堂
Thank you.
谢谢
Until tomorrow. then.
明天见
Oh. Virtue ...
哦，美德...
Silently and with fear, enter the hearts of all that hear me this day.
安静地、小心地进入 今天在座的各位心中
Will he kneel down when he asks her?
你想他会跪着说吗？
They always kneel down.
求婚都得下跪
What is wrong, dearest?
怎么了，亲爱的？
Willoughby? What is the matter?
卫乐比？怎么回事？
Forgive me ... l am sent ...
对不起...我奉命...
Lady Allen exercised the privilege of riches upon a dependent cousin.
艾夫人运用富人的特权...
- She is sending me to London. - This morning?
-你说呢？ -让我去嘛！我都快12岁了
What a disappointment. Your business won't detain you for long, l hope?
真是遗憾 你应该不会去很久吧？
You are kind. but l have no idea of returning immediately to Devonshire.
谢谢你的好意 可是我短期之内不会回来了
- l am invited only once a year. - Can you wait for our invitation?
-我一年祗被邀请来一次 -若是邀请你，可晚点再走吗？
My engagements are of such a nature ... l dare not flatter my ...
我的事情很紧急...我不敢...
lt's folly to linger in this manner. l will not torment myself further.
这样很不明智 我不想再折磨自己
Willoughby, come back!
卫乐比，回来！
Ask Betsy to make a cup of tea for Marianne.
请贝丝帮玛丽安泡杯茶
- What is wrong, my love? - Do not ask me questions.
-怎么回事？ -别问我
- They must have quarrelled. - That is unlikely.
-他们一定是吵架了 -不太像
Perhaps Lady Allen disapproves of his regard for Marianne.
也许是艾夫人 不赞成他们在一起
- An excuse to send him away. - Then why did he not say so?
-找藉口支开他 -那他为何不明说？
- lt's not like him to be secretive. - What do you suspect?
-他平常什么事都说的 -那你觉得是什么事呢？
- Why was his manner so guilty? - You think he's been acting a part?
-他为何面有愧色？ -你是说他一直都在做戏？
- No. He loves her. l am sure. - Of course!
-不，他爱她，这点我敢肯定 -他当然爱她
Has he left her any assurance of his return?
他有没有保证他会回来？
Ask if he proposed.
问问看他是否有求婚
No! l cannot force a confidence from Marianne. Neither should you.
不行！我不能去逼问她 你也不该
We must trust her to confide in us in her own time.
让她自己跟我们说
There was something underhand in his manner.
我总觉得他有问题
You will think the worst of him.
你对他有成见
l give him the benefit of my good opinion. He deserves no less.
我愿意相信他 我们都应该如此
l am very fond of Willoughby.
妈，我很喜欢卫乐比
Mamma ... Mamma!
妈...妈！
She would not let me in.
她不让我进去
- lf only this rain would stop. - lf only you would stop.
-雨停该有多好 -你能闭嘴更好
'Twas you took her off my hands, Mr. Palmer. A good bargain, too.
是你要娶我女儿的 而且算是便宜你了
Now l have the whip hand over you, for you cannot give her back.
现在我手上的牌比你强 因为你不能把人还给我
Marianne, play with us. Looking at the weather will not bring him back.
玛丽安，来玩牌 你这样，他也不会回来的
- She ate nothing at dinner. - We're all forlorn these days.
-她晚餐都没吃 -最近好无聊
Dear Miss Dashwood, perhaps now we might have our ... discussion.
戴小姐 我们可以...讨论了吧？
- Our discussion? - l've longed to ask you something.
-讨论？ -有件事我一直想请教你
You might think me impertinent. lt is an odd question.
就怕有点冒昧，这问题很突兀
lf only he'd gone to Combe Magna. We live but half a mile away.
如果卫先生回家了，我们可以 陪令妹找他，我们祗相距半哩
- Five and a half. - l cannot believe it is that far.
-是五哩半 -我不相信有那么远
- l can't believe it. - Try.
-我不相信 -试着相信
You may ask any manner of question if that is of any help.
你可以问我任何问题 如果我可以帮得上忙
Are you acquainted with your sister-in-law's mother Mrs. Ferrars?
你认识 你大嫂的母亲，费太太吗？
Fanny's mother? No. l have never met her.
芬妮的母亲？ 不，我没见过她
You must think me strange to ask. lf only l dared tell ...
你一定觉得奇怪 如果我告诉你…
lf she tells you of the famous Mr. F, you must pass it on.
如果她在说F先生的事 你可得要告诉我们
Will you take a turn with me, Miss Dashwood?
陪我走走好吗？
l had no idea you were at all connected with that family.
我不知道你跟她家有关系
l am nothing to Mrs. Ferrars at present.
我目前与费太太毫无关系
But the time may come when we may be very intimately connected.
但可能有这么一天 我会跟她相当亲近
What do you mean?
此话怎讲？
Do you have an understanding with Fanny's brother Robert?
你是否和芬妮的弟弟，罗伯 有了婚约？
The youngest? No. l have never met him in my life.
老么？不，我不曾见过他
- With Edward. - Edward Ferrars?
-是和爱德华 -爱德华费洛斯？
Edward and l have been secretly engaged these five years.
爱德华和我私订终身有五年了
You may well be surprised.
你一定很意外
l only mention it because l entirely trust you to keep our secret.
我知道你一定会保密才跟你说
Edward looks on you quite as his own sister.
爱德华拿你当妹妹看
l am sorry. Surely we ...
对不起，我们…
We surely do not mean the same Mr. Ferrars.
我们说的是不同的两个人吧？
Yes. He was under the tutelage of my uncle, Mr. Pratt, in Plymouth.
是同一人，我曾就读 我舅舅在普茅利斯主持的学校
- Has he never spoken of it? - Yes ... Yes. l believe he has.
-他没跟你提过？ -对…有的
l wanted his mother's approval, but we loved each other so much.
我希望得到他母亲的首肯 但我们相爱的无法自拔
You must have seen how capable he is of making a woman attached to him.
你应能体会 他很容易让女人倾心
l cannot pretend it has not been hard on both of us.
我们相爱得非常辛苦
We can scarcely meet above twice a year.
我们一年最多祗能见上二次面
You seem out of sorts. Are you quite well?
你好像有点不对劲 你还好吧？
- l have not offended you? - l must know what you are saying.
-我没冒犯你吧？ -我要知道你们在说什么
- Promise me you'll not tell a soul. - Miss Dashwood is quite engrossed.
-答应我，绝不说出去 戴小姐好像略有所思
l give you my word.
我答应你
- What has so fascinated you? - Tell us all!
-什么事让你兴致这么高？ -说来听听！
- We were talking of London. - Do you hear that, Charlotte?
-我们在谈伦敦的事 -你听到没有 夏洛特？
- Charlotte and l concocted a plan. - The best plan in the world!
-你们在说悄悄话的时候 夏洛特和我有了个想法
l make for London shortly, and l invite you, Lucy, -
世上最好的想法
- and both the Misses Dashwood to join me.
和两位戴小姐同行
Can l go?
-我可以去吗？ -你还小
You will all come to my Chelsea home and taste of the season's delights.
你们跟我住在雀尔喜 享受社交季节的活动
- Do you not long for it to be so? - l came here with no other view.
-她们就要去伦敦了 -我来就为了此事
- We can't leave our mother. - She can spare you very well.
-我们不能丢下家母一个人 -她不必你们操心
- Of course she can! - l could not be more delighted.
-一点也没错！ -我高兴都来不及
l will brook no refusal. Let us strike hands on the bargain.
我不许你拒绝，戴小姐 我们来握手约定
lf l don't have you married by Michaelmas, it will not be my fault.
如果你们九月还结不了婚 那就不是我的错！
l've never been so grateful.
我从来没这么感激过
l shall see Willoughby, and you will see Edward.
我可以见到卫乐比了 你也可以见到爱德华
- Are you asleep? - With you in the room?
-你睡着了？ -有你在我睡得着吗？
You can't feel as calm as you look. Oh, l will never sleep tonight.
你心里不可能像外表般平静 我今晚睡不着了
What were you and Miss Steele talking about so long?
你跟史小姐说了什么 说这么久？
Nothing of significance.
没什么重要的
How do you think l like poking about in that big house without Charlotte?
没有女儿陪着 自己一人怎会去住那大房子？
l wrote to Edward, yet l do not know how much l may see of him.
我写信给爱德华了 但不知我们能见几次面
Secrecy is vital. He'll never be able to call.
保密非常重要，他不能来找我
My only comfort has been the constancy of his affection.
还好他对我始终如一
You're fortunate never to have had any doubts on that score.
你很幸运，这么久了 你们之间没有疑虑
l am of a jealous nature. Had he talked more of one young woman ...
我可是个醋坛子 如果他多谈论哪个小姐…
But he's not given a moment's alarm on that count.
但他从来没让我操心过
lmagine how glad he'll be to learn that we are friends.
我们成了朋友 他一定很开心
- Have you missed me, Pigeon? - Very much, ma'am.
-皮基安，想不想我？ -想极了，夫人
- ls everything in order? - l suggest the ordering of coal.
-一切都很好吧？ -很好，但可能要买煤炭
There you are, Pooter. Still alive, l see ... Tea, Pigeon.
鹦鹉，你还活着 快泡茶，皮基安
You do not waste any time. Give it to Pigeon.
你真是分秒必争 交给皮基安处理
Mrs. Jennings says your sister will buy her wedding clothes in town.
詹太太说令妹要买婚纱
John and Fanny are in town. We should be forced to see them.
约翰和芬妮在镇上 我们得去见他们
l think it was for next door.
是找隔壁的？
Sit down for two seconds. You're making me nervous.
你坐下吧 你这样让我好紧张
Oh, Elinor, it is Willoughby.
爱琳娜，是卫乐比
lndeed it is.
是真的
Excuse me. Colonel.
对不起，上校
Colonel ...
上校…
What a pleasure to see you. Have you been in London all this while?
真高兴见到你 你一直在伦敦吗？
l have heard reports through town ...
我在镇上听到消息…
Tell me once and for all:
请你直接了当的说吧
ls everything resolved between your sister and Mr. Willoughby?
令妹跟卫先生的事决定了没？
Though neither one has informed me of their understanding, -
他们都没告诉我是否有约定
- l have no doubt of their mutual affection.
但我知道他们是彼此相爱
Thank you, Miss Dashwood.
谢谢你，戴小姐
To your sister l wish all imaginable happiness.
我祝令妹一切美满幸福
To Mr. Willoughby, that he may endeavour to deserve her.
至于卫先生 愿他好自为之让她幸福
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
Forgive me ...
请原谅，我…
Forgive me.
原谅我
- Where is dear Edward. John? - And who is Edward?
-约翰，爱德华呢？ -爱德华是谁？
My brother. Mr. Edward Ferrars.
是舍弟，爱德华费洛斯
Ferrars with an F?
费洛斯是F开头吗？
Are there any messages? No message at all? No cards?
有没有消息？ 什么都没有？没卡片？
- You do not ask for your messages. - No, for l do not expect any.
-你都不问有没有信 -对，我没有等信
l have very little acquaintance in town.
我在这里没有什么熟人
Not another word about the ham bone. You and Cartwright sort it out.
别跟我嘀咕 你们自己去解决
- No messages. - Do not fret, my dear.
-没有消息，夫人 -别着急，亲爱的
This good weather is keeping many a sportsman in the country.
因为天气很好 很多人到乡下打球
But the frost will soon drive them to town. Depend on it.
但一下霜 他们保证很快就回来
l had not thought of that.
我怎么没想到
And Miss Dashwood may set her heart at rest, -
戴小姐可以放心了
- for your sister-in-law is inviting Mr. F to the ball tonight.
听说你大嫂 今晚要邀请F先生参加舞会
Do be careful. the horses have been here.
小心马粪
lt is beginning to rain also. Follow me.
快下雨了，跟我来
Mamma! This is very merry!
妈！好热闹啊！
- Do you spy anyone we know? - No. Mr. Palmer has a better view.
-有没认识的人？ -巴先生比较高，叫他看
- Do you see anyone we know? - Unfortunately not.
-巴先生，有看到熟人吗？ -可惜没有
How can you be such a tease? There is Mrs. John Dashwood.
你真爱捉弄人 那不是约翰戴虚伍夫人吗？
Come along, my dears.
亲爱的，快跟我来
There you are!
你们在这里！
How hot it is ... You are not alone. l trust?
这里好热…你有伴吧？
John is just gone to fetch my brother.
约翰去找舍弟了
Your brother! l declare. this is good news, indeed.
令弟来了！真是好消息
l shall faint clean away.
我一定马上昏倒
Mrs. Jennings, l am pleased to meet you. My brother-in-law ...
詹太太，真高兴见到你 这位是我的小舅子…
Mr. Robert Ferrars.
罗伯费洛斯
Miss Dashwood. Miss Steele. Miss Marianne.
戴小姐，史小姐，玛丽安
My dear ladies, we meet at last.
各位小姐，我们终于见面了
You must be the younger brother. ls Mr. Edward not here?
你是弟弟吗？爱德华没来吗？
- Miss Dashwood was counting on him. - He is far too busy.
-戴小姐以为他会来 -他太忙了
There's no special acquaintance here to make his attendance worthwhile.
况且这里没他认识的人 来了没啥意思
What are the men about these days? Are they in hiding?
时下的年青人都在做什么？ 全都躲起来了？
ln the absence of your brother you must dance with Miss Dashwood.
既然你哥哥没来 你得和戴小姐跳支舞
lt would be my honour.
这是我的荣幸
Perhaps Miss SteeIe might consider reserving the allemande?
或许史小姐也能赏光
You reside in Devonshire. Miss Dashwood?
戴小姐，你住在迪凡郡吧？
- ln a cottage? - Yes.
-住的是一间小屋？ -是的
l am excessively fond of a cottage.
我非常喜欢小屋
lf l had any money to spare, l should build one myself.
我若有余钱，也会盖一间
Mr. Willoughby ...
卫先生…
- How do you do, Miss Dashwood? - Very well.
-你好吗，戴小姐？ 很好，谢谢
- How is your family? - We are all extremely well.
-家人好吗？ -我们都很好
Thank you for your kind inquiry.
谢谢你的关心
Willoughby!
卫乐比！
Good God, Willoughby ...
天啊，卫乐比…
Will you not shake hands with me?
你不跟我握手吗？
How do you do, Miss Marianne?
你好，玛丽安
What is the matter? Why have you not come to see me?
怎么了？你怎么都不来看我？
Were you not in London? Have you not received my letters?
你之前不在伦敦吗？ 有没有收到我的信？
l had the pleasure of receiving the information you sent to me.
谢谢你写信给我
For heaven's sake, Willoughby, tell me what is wrong.
看在老天份上，卫乐比 告诉我怎么回事？
Thank you. l am most obliged.
谢谢，我很感激
Excuse me, I must rejoin my party.
恕我失陪，朋友在等我
Go to him. Force him to come to me instantly.
去找他，叫他马上过来
You must come away.
玛丽安，我们走吧
- Do you know them? - Acquaintances from the country.
-你认识她们吗？ -乡下来的
Come away, dearest.
走吧，亲爱的
l do not understand. l must speak to him ...
我不懂，我一定要跟他说清楚
My goodness. Come, dear. You need some air.
天啊，走，亲爱的 出去透透气
Lucy! We must go.
露茜！我们要走了
lt would be our pleasure to escort your young charge home.
如果我们能送她回家 这将是我们的荣幸
How kind.
你人真好
She actually sent him messages during the night?
她真的在晚上叫人捎信给他？
- Marianne, please tell me. - Do not ask me questions.
-玛丽安，拜托你告诉我 -别问我
- You have no confidence in me. - You confide in no one.
-你都不信任我 -你自己还不是都不说
- l have nothing to tell. - We neither of us do.
-我没有什么好说的 -那我们都没话可说
l, because l conceal nothing. You, because you communicate nothing.
毕竟我是毫无秘密 你则是守口如瓶
Lady Charteris ought to limit her invitation list. lt was very warm.
查夫人应该别请这么多客人 昨晚可把我给热死了
l am glad we left early.
幸好我们能提早离开
There now ...
来了吧
Lovers' quarrels are swift to heal. That letter will do the trick.
爱人吵得凶也去得快 看了信准没事
l must be off. l do hope he doesn't keep her waiting much longer.
我得走了 希望他别让她等太久
lt hurts to see her this way.
真不忍心看她如此难过
What a welcome l had from Edward's family.
爱德华的家人都很欢迎我
You never said how agreeable your sister-in-law is. Robert, also.
你大嫂人这么好，你都没说 还有罗伯人也是
It is fortunate that none of them knows of your engagement.
幸好他们都不知道你的秘密
''Dear Madam. l am at a loss to see how l might have offended you.''
“亲爱的小姐 我完全不清楚有何无礼之处”
''lf l have given rise to a belief of more than l meant to express, -
“如果我行为 若有任何误导之嫌”
- l regret not having been more guarded.''
“我后悔自己不够谨慎”
''My affections are engaged elsewhere.''
“我心早有所属”
''lt is with regret that l return your letters and the lock of hair.''
“很遗憾得奉还来函 及你相赠之秀发”
''l am, et cetera, John Willoughby.''
“谨此，约翰卫乐比”
Dearest ...
亲爱的…
lt is better than if your engagement had carried on before he ended it.
这总比订下婚约许久后 他才反悔得好
We're not engaged.
我们没有婚约
l thought he left you with some kind of understanding.
我以为你们有了约定
- He's not so unworthy as you think. - Did he tell you that he loved you?
-他没你想像中那么坏 -他有没有说他爱你？
Yes. No ... Never absolutely. lt was implied but never declared.
有，没有…没明白的说 常有暗示但没明说
Sometimes l thought it had been, but it never was. He broke no vow.
有时我以为说了 但却不是，他没违背誓言
He made us all believe he loved you.
他让我们都以为他爱你
He did! He loved me as l loved him.
他是爱我的！ 他爱我，像我爱他一样
l had to come straight up. How are you, Miss Marianne?
我刚刚听说了 你还好吧，玛丽安
Poor thing, she looks very bad. No wonder. for it is but too true.
可怜，她看来好伤心 也难怪，一点也错不了
l was told by Miss Morton, -
听莫小姐说…
- that he is soon to marry a Miss Grey with 50,000!
他即将迎娶 身价5万镑的盖小姐为妻
lf true, he is a good-for-nothing who used my young friend ill.
若是真的 那他就是狼心狗肺的东西
And l wish with all my soul that his wife might plague all his heart out.
我希望他被老婆折磨一辈子
He's not the only young man worth having.
世上又不祗他一个男人
With your pretty face you'll never want for admirers.
你那么漂亮，还怕没人要吗
Better let her have her cry out and have done with it.
最好让她发泄一下 哭完就没事了
l will go look out something to tempt her.
我去给她买点东西安慰她
- Does she care for olives? - l cannot tell you.
-她喜不喜欢橄榄？ -我不清楚
Apparently, they never were engaged.
他们显然并无婚约
Miss Grey has 50,000. Marianne is virtually penniless.
盖小姐有5万英镑 玛丽安却穷得很
She couldn't expect him to go through with it. But l feel for her.
她不能指望人家娶她 但我替玛丽安惋惜
She will lose her bloom and end a spinster like Elinor.
她会变得憔悴 和爱琳娜一样变成老处女
We might have them to stay for a few days. We are, after all, family.
我们不妨请她们来住几天 毕竟我们是一家人
- And my father ... - My love ...
-何况父亲… -亲爱的…
l would ask them with all my heart, but l've already asked Miss Steele.
我非常赞成 但我已经邀请了史小姐
And we cannot deprive Mrs. Jennings of all her company.
我们不能让詹太太没了伴
We can invite your sisters some other year.
我们可以改年再邀请你妹妹
Miss Steele will profit more from your generosity, poor girl.
史小姐才真的需要招待 可怜的女孩
Excellent notion.
好主意
Colonel Brandon to see you.
布上校来看您了，戴小姐
l must get her home. Palmer can take us to Cleveland, a day from Barton.
我得尽快送她回家，巴先生可带 我们至他家，离巴顿有一天车程
- l'll take you to Barton myself. - l confess, that is what l hoped.
-我亲自送你们到回家 -我就希望你能帮忙
Marianne suffers cruelly.
玛丽安受了很大的打击
What pains me most is how hard she tries to justify Mr. Willoughby.
令我最难过的是 她还替卫乐比辩解
Perhaps ...
也许…
May l relate some circumstances which only a desire to be useful ...
我能否说明一件事 我是纯粹出自好意…
You have something to tell me of Mr. Willoughby?
是有关卫乐比的事？
When l quitted Barton last ...
我离开巴顿的时候…
No, l must go further back.
不，还要更早
No doubt ... No doubt ...
毫无疑问…
... Mrs. Jennings has appraised you of certain events in my past.
想必詹太太跟你谈过我的过去
The sad outcome of my connection with a young woman named Eliza.
我跟伊丽莎交往的不幸结局
What is not commonly known -
大家不知道的是…
- is that 20 years ago, before she died. Eliza bore a child.
20年前 她去世前生下一名私生女
The father. whoever he was. abandoned them.
孩子的父亲将她们遗弃
As Eliza lay dying, she begged me to look after the child.
伊丽莎临终前 求我替她照顾小孩
l had failed her in ever other way, l could not refuse her now.
我对不起她，此刻哪能拒绝
l placed the child, Beth, with a family in the country -
我把孩子贝丝，带到乡下…
- where l knew she would be looked after. l saw her whenever l could.
请人照顾，我尽可能常去看她
She grew up so headstrong, -
长大后她脾气非常倔强
- and, God forgive me, l allowed her too much freedom.
上帝原谅我 我太宠她，让她太自由了
Almost a year ago she disappeared.
约一年前，她失踪了
l instigated a search, but for eight months l imagined the worst.
我请人寻找 但八个月来杳无音讯
On the day of the Delaford picnic, l received the first news of her.
但在野餐那天 我得到了她的消息
She was ... with child.
她…怀孕了
And the blackguard who had left her with no hint of his whereabouts ...
那男的离她而去，不知去向
Do you mean Willoughby?
你是指卫乐比？
Before l could confront him. Lady Allen had turned him out.
我还没去找他证实 艾夫人听说后便撵他走
- He fled to London. - He left without any explanation.
-他就跑来伦敦 -他那天没解释就走了
He risked losing the estate, and the money that remained to his debtors.
他的庄园可能要用来抵债
So he abandoned Marianne -
所以他舍弃玛丽安
- for Miss Grey and her 50.000.
去娶有钱的盖小姐为妻
ls Beth still in town?
贝丝还在城里吗？
She has chosen to go to the country for her confinement.
她选择回乡下待产
l would not burden you, had l not, from my heart, -
我说这些不是要让你难过
- believed it might, in time, lessen your sister's regrets.
祗因为我相信 这或能化解令妹的遗憾
l have described Mr. Willoughby as the worst of libertines.
我把卫先生形容得很放荡
But l learned from Lady Allen that he did mean to propose that day.
但艾夫人告诉我 他那天的确有意求婚
l cannot deny that his intentions towards Marianne were honourable.
我不能否认他对玛丽安 原本是真心真意的
l feel certain that he would have married her.
我相信他原本会娶她
- Had it not been ... - For the money.
-要不是有… -钱的问题
- Was l right to tell you? - Of course.
-我全说了，这样对吗？ -当然
Whatever his past actions, whatever his present course, -
不管他过去怎样，今后如何
- you may be certain that he loved you.
可以确定的是他爱过你
But not enough.
但还不够深
Not enough ...
不够深…
Here is someone to cheer you up.
我给你找了个伴
How is your dear sister? Poor thing.
你妹妹好吗，戴小姐 真可怜
l do not know what I'd do if a man treated me with so little respect.
我若给男人这般对待 真不知该怎么办
Are you enjoying your stay with John and Fanny?
你在约翰家住得还好吧？
l was never so happy in my life. Your sister-in-law has taken to me.
我这辈子从来没这么开心过 我想你大嫂喜欢我
- You cannot imagine what happened. - No. l cannot.
-有件事你一定猜不到 -我是猜不到
Yesterday l was introduced to his mother. She was more than civil.
昨天我见了爱德华的母亲 她对我不祗客气而已
l have not yet seen Edward, but l feel sure to, very soon.
我还没见到爱德华 但应该快了
There is a Mr. Edward Ferrars to see you.
有位爱德华费洛斯找您 戴小姐
Do ask him to come in.
请他进来
What a pleasure to see you. You know Miss Steele. of course.
真高兴见到你 你一定认识史小姐吧？
- How do you do, Miss Steele? - l am well, thank you.
-你好吗，史小姐？ -我很好，谢谢
Do sit down.
请坐
Are you surprised to find me here and not at your sister's house?
你很意外会在这见到我 你以为我在令姐家吧？
Let me fetch Marianne. She would be disappointed to miss you.
我去叫玛丽安 她一定很想见你
Edward! l heard your voice.
爱德华！我听到你的声音
- At last you found us. - My visit is shamefully overdue.
-你终于来了 -我不该这么晚才来拜访
- You're pale. Are you not well? - Don't think of me. Elinor is well.
-你脸色好苍白，你生病了？ -别管我，爱琳娜好好的
- That is enough for both of us. - How do you enjoy London?
-我们该满足了 -还喜欢伦敦吗？
The sight of you is all the pleasure it has afforded. ls that not so?
祗有见到你，才有乐趣 对不对，爱琳娜？
- Why have you not visited before? - l have been engaged elsewhere.
-你怎么现在才来看我们？ -我有事走不开
But what was that when there were such friends to be met?
比跟朋友见面还重要吗？
Perhaps you think young men never honour their engagements?
或许你认为年轻的男人 都不遵守约定
Edward is the most incapable of being selfish of anyone l ever saw.
爱德华是我认识 所最不自私的人
Edward, will you not sit? Help me to persuade him.
爱德华，怎么不坐 爱琳娜，你叫他坐
- Forgive me. l must take my leave. - You are only just arrived.
-对不起，我得走了 -你才刚到
l've an urgent commission for Fanny.
我得替芬妮办点急事
Perhaps you might escort me back to your sister's house.
那你能送我回令姐家吗？
lt would be an honour.
这是我的荣幸
- Why did you not urge him to stay? - He must have had his reasons.
-你怎么不留住他？ -他要走，  自然有原因
Yes, your coldness. Were l Edward, l'd assume you didn't care for me.
那一定是你太冷淡，换作我 我也会认为你不喜欢我
Marianne looked badly. lt makes me fear that l shall never marry.
玛丽安那天好可怜 害我不敢结婚
Nonsense. You will marry far better than the Dashwood girls.
胡说 你的归宿会比戴家她们都好
But l have no dowry.
可是我没有嫁妆
There are other important qualities that you have in abundance.
你还有其他美德足以弥补
lt would not surprise me if you married beyond your expectations.
说不定你的婆家 远比你想像的好
Oh, l wish that might be so.
能那样就好了
There is a young man ...
是有一个人…
ls he of good fortune and breeding?
他的家境、背景好吗？
Of both. But his family would certainly oppose the match.
都很好 但他的家人一定会反对
They will allow it as soon as they see you.
他们一见到你就一定会赞同的
lt is a very great secret.
这是天大的秘密
l've told nobody in the world for fear of discovery.
我谁都没说，深怕被人发现
- l am the soul of discretion. - lf l dared tell ...
-我这个人最靠得住 -如果我说出来…
l can assure you, l am as silent as the grave.
我保证，我绝对守口如瓶
Viper in my bosom!
真大胆，敢在太岁头上动土！
Stop this!
住手！给我滚！
What a commotion! Edward Ferrars. the one l used to joke you about, -
天下大乱了！ 我拿来开玩笑的那位费先生
- is engaged these five years to Lucy Steele.
已经跟史小姐订婚5年了
His mother has demanded he break the engagement or suffer disinheritance.
他母亲要求他解除婚约 否则将撤消他的继承权
But he refuses to break his promise. He has stood by her, -
但他拒绝毁约，他坚持要娶她
- and is cut off without a penny. She settled it all on Mr. Robert.
他一毛钱也不要 他妈就把家产给了罗伯
l must find Lucy. Your sister-in-law drove her to hysteria.
我要去找露茜 她被你嫂子臭骂了一顿
How long have you known?
这件事你知道多久了？
- Since Mrs. Jennings invited us. - Why did you not tell me?
-詹太太选我们来伦敦那晚 -你为何不告诉我？
Lucy told me in confidence.
露茜叫我不要说出去
- l could not break my word. - He loves you!
-我不能食言 -他爱你！
- He tried to tell me about Lucy. - He cannot marry her.
-他试着告诉我露茜的事 -他不能娶她
Should he treat her worse than Willoughby treated you?
你要露茜的遭遇比你还惨吗？
- He can't marry without love. - He promised a long time ago.
-他不能娶自己不爱的人啊！ -他们早有约定
He may harbour some regret, but he he will be happy he kept his word.
他或许有些后悔 但他会很高兴自己信守承诺
lt is bewitching to think one's happiness depends on one person, -
我们希望从别人身上找到幸福
- but it is not always possible. We must accept.
却未必能够找到，认命吧
Edward will marry Lucy, and you and l will go home.
爱德华会娶露茜 而你和我就回家
Always resignation and acceptance.
你总是听天由命
Always prudence and honour and duty.
总是有百般顾虑
Elinor, where is your heart?
爱琳娜，你的心在哪里？
What do you know of my heart, or anything but your own suffering?
你怎会了解我的心？ 你知道自己的痛苦
For weeks this has been pressed on me, when l could not speak of it.
这秘密一直闷在我心里 我不能跟任何人说
Forced on me by the person whose prior claims ruined all my hopes.
而告诉我的人 就是夺走我希望的人
l endured her exaltation, knowing l was divided from Edward forever.
我听她一再的夸赞 自知和爱德华永无结果
lf not bound to silence. l'd have produced proof of a broken heart.
如果我能说的话 你就会明白我的心有多痛
l have heard your Mr. Ferrars has lost his fortune to his brother.
听说你朋友的继承权 被转至他弟弟名下
- Have l been rightly informed? - lt is indeed so.
-这消息正确吗？ -没错
- Are you acquainted with him? - No. we have never met.
-你认识费先生吗？ -我们未曾见过面
But l know only too well the cruelty ...
但我太清楚那种残酷
... of dividing two young people long attached to one another.
活生生的拆散一对情侣
l have a proposal that may allow him to marry Miss Steele immediately.
我有个办法 能让他即刻迎娶史小姐
As he is a friend to your family, perhaps you'd mention it to him.
既然他是你们的好友 我想请你去跟他说
l'm sure he'd be delighted to hear it from your own lips.
你亲自去说 我想他一定很高兴
l think not.
我不这么认为
His behaviour has proved him proud. ln the best sense.
他很重面子，这是在说他好
l feel certain this is the right course.
我相信这样比较好
Mr. Edward Ferrars.
爱德华费洛斯先生
Thank you for responding so quickly.
谢谢你这么快就来
l was grateful to receive your message.
我很高兴接获你的通知
God knows what you must think of me.
不知你会怎么想我…
- l have no right to speak ... - l have good news.
-我自知无权多说… -我有好消息
Do please sit down.
请坐
- You know of Col. Brandon. - l've heard his name.
-你知道布上校吧？ -听说过
Col. Brandon desires me to say, as you wish to join the clergy, -
布上校要我转告你 他知道你想当牧师
- that he has pleasure in offering you the parish at Delaford, -
-便想请你主持他的教区
- in the hope it may enable you and Miss Steele to marry.
-你和史小姐便可结婚
- Col. Brandon? - Yes.
-布上校？ -是的
He means it as testimony of his concern for this cruel situation.
他是想表示对你们困境的关心
Col. Brandon give me a parish?
布上校要我主持教区？
Can it be possible?
有可能吗？
You shouldn't be astonished to find friendship outside your family.
你不能因为家人的绝情 而拒人于千里之外
No. Not to find it in you.
不，我不是针对你
l cannot be ignorant that it is certainly to you that l owe this.
我知道这一切都是你促成的
l'd express it if l could, but l am no orator ...
我希望我能表达 但我不善言词…
You are mistaken. You owe it to your own merit.
你误会了 这是你自己得来的
Col. Brandon must be a man of great worth.
布上校的人品一定十分高尚
He is the kindest and best of men.
他是世上最好的人
May l ask why the colonel did not tell me himself?
布上校为何不亲自跟我说？
l think he felt it would be better coming from a friend.
我想他觉得透过朋友比较好
Your friendship has been the most important in my life.
你是我一生中最重要的朋友
You will always have it.
我永远是你的朋友
Forgive me.
原谅我
You honour your promises. That is more important than anything else.
你实践你的承诺 这比什么都重要
l wish you both happiness.
祝你们幸福美满
What luck for them to find a parish so close to Barton.
真是幸运 能找到离家近的教区
You'll all be able to meet very often.
我们可以常见面
l've never disliked a person so much as l do Mr. Willoughby.
我讨厌死卫乐比了
We can see his house from the hill! l'll ask Jackson to plant trees.
从我们的小山可以看到 他的房子，我要在山上种大树
You won't.
不可以
l hear Miss Grey's bridal gown was everything of the finest ...
听说盖小姐的婚纱好漂亮…
Mrs. Bunting! We're in desperate need of tea.
班太太 我们快渴死了，快泡茶
She's not drawn breath since London. Had l only found another way home.
她一路讲，连气都没换 早该另想办法回家
There was no other way. l'll just take a stroll. A moment's peace.
没别的办法 我想走一走，静一下
- l think it is going to rain. - No. it will not rain.
-好像快下雨了 -不会的
- When you say so, it always does. - l shall keep to the garden.
-每次你说不会就一定下 -我就在花园里，不会走远
We are very proud of our Thomas. His papa has such a way with him.
我们很喜欢这孩子 他爸爸最会逗他
Oh, there you are. Come and meet little Thomas.
你在这儿呀！ 快来看看汤姆士
l cannot see Marianne.
我看不到玛丽安
Love is not love which alters when it alteration finds. -
说变心就变心，哪能算是爱
- or bends with the remover to remove.
哪能任凭抹灭
Oh. no. 'tis an ever fixed mark -
不，爱是永不褪色的印记
- that looks on tempests and is never shaken.
纵使有狂风暴雨 也永不动摇
Willoughby ...
卫乐比…
Marianne?
玛丽安？
- She'll be wet through. - Thank you for pointing that out.
-她一定会成落汤鸡 -谢谢你提醒
Do not worry, Miss Dashwood. Brandon will find her.
放心吧，戴小姐 布莱登会找到她的
We can all guess where she went.
我们都猜得出她去哪了
She's not hurt. but we must get her warm.
她没受伤 得快点给她取暖
There is a fire lit in my room. Do hurry!
我房里生了火，快点
l think Marianne may need a doctor.
我想得帮玛丽安请大夫
You'll wear yourself out. A day or two in bed will set her to rights.
你会把自己累坏的，上校 别担心，躺一两天就好了
You can rely upon Harris, Colonel. l've never found a better physician.
哈大夫医术很高明，放心吧
- What is the diagnosis? - lt is an infectious fever.
-是什么问题？ -是一种会传染的热病
- l recommend removing your child. - Mrs. Bunting!
-我建议快将婴儿隔离 -班太太！
Miss Dashwood ... l am more sorry than l can say.
戴小姐…我不知该怎么说
- lf you prefer me to stay l shall. - That is very kind.
-你要我留下的话我愿意 -谢谢你的好意
But Col. Brandon and Dr. Harris will look after us.
但布上校和哈大夫会照顾我们
Thank you for all you have done.
谢谢你所做的一切
She's not doing as well as l would like.
她的病情没有好转
What can l do?
我能做什么？
- You've done so much already. - Anything, or l shall run mad.
-你已经帮很多忙了 -给我点事做，不然我会发疯
She would be easier if her mother were here.
家母在会好一些
l must fetch more laudanum.
我再去拿镇定剂
l cannot pretend that your sister's condition is not very serious.
我不能骗你说 令妹的病情不严重
You must prepare yourself.
你要有心里准备
l will return shortly.
我马上回来
Marianne ...
玛丽安
Marianne, please try ...
玛丽安，你要振作
Please try ...
拜托你振作点…
l cannot ... l cannot do without you.
我不能…我不能没有你
l've tried to bear everything else. l will try ...
别的事我都可设法忍受 我会设法…
But please, dearest ...
可是求求你，亲爱的…
... beloved Marianne ...
亲爱的玛丽安…
... do not leave me alone.
别丢下我一人
Elinor ...
爱琳娜…
My mother ...
是我母亲…
She is out of danger. She is out of danger.
她脱离险境了 她脱离险境了
- Where is Elinor? - l'm here.
-爱琳娜呢？ -我在这里
Dearest. l am here.
亲爱的，我在这里
Col. Brandon ...
布上校…
Thank you.
谢谢你
He's not so dashing as Willoughby, but he has a pleasing countenance.
他不如卫乐比潇洒 但亲切稳重得多
There was something in Willoughby's eyes at times that l did not like.
我当时总觉得 不喜欢卫乐比的眼神
''Nor is the earth the lesse. or loseth aught.''
“大地毫无消失 依然如故”
''What from one place doth fall is with the tide to another brought.''
“不论何物，落入海中 终为潮水，流至他处”
''For there is nothing lost but may be found ...
“有所失，就有所得”
... if sought.''
只需追求
- Shall we continue tomorrow? - No, for l must away.
-明天再继续好吗？ -不行，我有远行
- Away? Where? - That l cannot tell you.
-远行？去哪？ -我不能说
lt is a secret.
这是个秘密
You will not stay away long?
你不会去很久吧？
There.
就是那里
There l fell. and there l first saw Willoughby.
我就在那里跌倒 遇见卫乐比的
Poor Willoughby. He will always regret you.
可怜的卫乐比 没娶你，他会后悔的
Does it follow that. had he chosen me. he would have been content?
但娶了我他会满足吗？
He would have had a wife he loved. but no money, -
纵然有心爱的人但身无分文
- and might have learned to rank his pocketbook above his heart.
可能很快会先考虑钱 然后才是爱情
lf his regrets are half as painful as mine, he will suffer enough.
他若有我一半后悔 就够他受的了
Do you compare your conduct with his?
你拿你的行为跟他比？
l compare it to what it ought to have been. With yours.
我是跟常理做比较 跟你的行为做比较
l fetched those beef fillets. ma'am.
牛肉买回来了
Beef is less expensive in Exeter. Anyway, it's for Marianne.
镇上牛肉比较便宜 是给玛丽安补的
- Was Exeter crowded? - lt was. ma'am.
-镇上人很多吗？ -很多
Miss Pothington has had another stroke.
白太太又中风了
And Miss Murden has turned away Coles for his drunkenness.
还有科斯因为酗酒 而被莫小姐开除了
And Mr. Ferrars is married. but of course you know that.
费先生结婚了 这你们早已知道
Who told you he was married?
谁告诉你他结婚了？
l saw Mrs. Ferrars myself. She and Mr. Ferrars stopped at the inn.
我碰到费太太了 她跟费先生在旅馆歇脚
l saw it was Miss Steele. so l took off my hat.
我经过时看到史小姐 就跟她请安
She inquired after all of you, especially Miss Dashwood.
她问到夫人、还有小姐们 特别是大小姐
She bade me give their compliments. They're sending a piece of the cake.
她要我代他们夫妇问候你们 还说会送蛋糕来
- Did Mrs. Ferrars seem well? - She said she was vastly contented.
-费太太气色好吗？ -好得很，她说她非常满足
As she was always an affable lady, l made free to wish herjoy.
因为她做人很好 我就给她祝福
Thank you, Thomas.
谢谢你，汤玛士
- What is it. Thomas? - I'm not sure, but it's heavy.
-是什么，汤玛士？ -不知道，挺重的
''lt is small enough for the parlour. When l follow shortly, l expect -
总算找到适合贵府的琴 将于日内造访
- that you've learnt the enclosed. Your friend, Christopher Brandon.''
希望届时能聆听所附曲目 挚友布莱登敬上
lt fits perfectly.
刚刚好
Here you are, Miss Marianne.
椅子来了，玛丽安
Fetch some tea.
泡些茶吧
- He must like you very much. - lt's for all of us.
-他一定很喜欢你 -这不是我一个人的，是大家的
Here is Col. Brandon.
布上校来了，玛丽安
- l do not think it is the coloneI. - He said he would arrive today.
-好像不是他 -他说他今天会到
Edward!
爱德华！
lt is Edward!
是爱德华！
Calm. We must be calm.
冷静，我们要冷静
Mr. Ferrars for you, ma'am.
费先生来了，夫人
Edward ... What a pleasure to see you.
爱德华…真高兴见到你
- l trust l find you all well? - Thank you. We are all very well.
-你们都好吧？ -谢谢你，我们都很好
We've been enjoying fine weather ... Well. we have .
近来天气很好…本来就是
l'm glad to hear it. The roads were very dry.
很高兴听你这么说 马路都很干
l wish you great joy, Edward.
我祝你一切幸福，爱德华
l hope you have left Mrs. Ferrars well.
费太太身体好吧？
Tolerably ... Thank you.
还可以…谢谢
ls Mrs. Ferrars at the new parish?
费太太人在新教区吗？
No ... my mother is in town.
不，家母在城里
l meant Mrs. Edward Ferrars.
我是问尊夫人
You've not heard?
你们没有听说吧？
l think you mean my brother. Mrs. Robert Ferrars.
我想你指的是舍弟 罗伯的太太
- Mrs. Robert Ferrars? - Yes.
-罗伯的太太？ -是的
l received a letter from Miss Steele. -
我收到一封史小姐的来信
- or Mrs. Ferrars, l should say, communicating to me -
应该说是费太太 她在信中说…
- the transfer of her affections to my brother Robert.
她爱上了舍弟罗伯
lt seems they were much thrown together in London.
他们在伦敦相处愉快
ln view of my new circumstances l felt it only right -
既然情况有所改变 我觉得…
- that she be released from our engagement.
她不该再受婚约约束
At any rate, they were married last week in Plymouth.
他们上周在普利茅斯结婚了
Then you ...
那你…
... are not married?
没有结婚？
No.
没有
Elinor ... l met Lucy when l was very young.
爱琳娜… 我认识露茜时，还很年轻
Had l had a profession, l would not have felt such an idle inclination.
我若有职业 就不会有那种愚蠢的念头
At Norland, l convinced myself that you felt only friendship for me, -
我在诺兰的行为很不恰当 但我深信你对我祗是友谊…
- and that it was my heart alone that l was risking.
…是我在拿良心来冒险
l have come with no expectations, only to express, now I am able, -
我今天来并不抱任何期望 祗想告诉你，我…
- that my heart is, and always will be ...
我的心，而且将永远是…
... yours.
属于你的
- He's sitting next to her. - What else?
-他坐在她旁边 -还有呢？
Tell us!
快说！
He's kneeling down!
他跪下来了！